hello I'm your host David Barnard and my
guest today is Marcus Burke a
subscription growth consultant who
specializes in unlocking meta as the
primary growth channel for your app on
the podcast I talk with Marcus about the
past current and future of meta ads
tactics to scale subscription apps on
meta and why you should probably exclude
younger audiences in your targeting hey
Marcus thanks so much for joining me on
the podcast today hi David super excited
to be here I listen to like almost every
episode of this since 2020 one of the
few podcasts I listen to very regularly
so yeah really really excited for this
one awesome well it's so good to have
you on and long time coming I've been
following your work as well you've done
a lot of great posts on LinkedIn anybody
who doesn't follow Marcus on LinkedIn go
to the show notes or search his name
Marcus Burke and find him on LinkedIn
because he's constantly sharing all
sorts of great stuff so I've been
meaning to have you on the podcast a
while and I'm especially excited about
the topic today so we are going to talk
about meta ads so Facebook Instagram you
probably know all the different plac I
don't even know all the different
placements that you can have with meta
ads but you know a lot of people have
used meta ads over the years
successfully
unsuccessfully it's one of the more
talked about channels in subscription
apps and so the first thing I wanted to
discuss is why like why meta ads why is
it such a talked about about Channel why
should sub subscription apps consider it
should all subscription apps consider it
so let's just start with that like why
meta ads you should definitely consider
it I don't think there are many apps out
there that can just say meta isn't for
me one of the big things of course is
that meta's family of apps is just
gigantic I think they recently shared
again that they have around about four
billion monthly active users across all
of their apps so as you already
mentioned Facebook Instagram but then
also all the sub placements do you know
if they D that so would that be is that
like actually 4 billion unique humans or
is that 4 billion like maybe there's a
billion overlap of people who use both
Facebook and Instagram do you know I
think it's duped but it also includes
WhatsApp of course which isn't all like
I think there's ads by now on WhatsApp
but you don't run them through meta ads
manager so that of course kind of bloats
it up a bit but still even if it's just
three or two billion um you can pretty
surely find your target audience on this
channel the other important thing is
that meta has a very very strong
algorithm they're good at finding your
audience for you it got a bit more
complicated with at and scan and I'm
sure we'll talk about that later on but
still meta's algorithm is really
unchallenged they had their SDK in many
many of the apps out there for years
they had their pixel on almost every
website for the last 10 years so they
sit just on a ton of data and they
really know how to build these customer
profiles and use the signal that you're
sending them to find your perfect
customer and that's really where the
magic happens so that you don't have to
care that much about how do I Target and
like who is my Target customer but you
can really find them in collaboration
with meta yeah that's one of the
interesting things I mean if you think
about and this is why I think it was
important to start with their scale and
the reach and why they matter cuz when
you think about those two things
combined three 4 billion people whatever
it is fully duped or people who actually
see ads it's in the billions and so then
you combine most people that would ever
subscribe to your app are probably using
one of meta's products that they do see
ads in and then meta is really good at
targeting your specific product to the
niches that it would appeal to so like
you know maybe like a super duper duper
duper Niche app would just not have the
scale to work on meta ads and then
there's all sorts of other reasons with
funnel and other reasons that meta ads
might not be performant for an
individual app but broadly speaking any
human that might subscribe to your app
is probably a meta and meta is really
good at finding them so it kind of makes
sense this is why they make tens of
billions of dollars of profit a year
right yeah it's a strong combination and
what I also like about the channel is
that in in the end all of it is native
advertisement and you can really go onto
these placements you can see what those
ads look like you can see what other
content is on these placements so you
get a pretty good understanding of like
what can I do here how can I be creative
to really insert my product onto them
while with a lot of other channels they
are like display networks you don't know
what's going on there's fraud which
doesn't happen on meta so really it's a
safe environment you have a good
understanding of what your final ad will
look like and I I think that's just a
very big Advantage as you're trying to
validate your app in the beginning
because if you don't know the context in
which your ads was shown then you can
never be sure if the data that you
gathered was in the end even valid yeah
and then another thing too is that the
ads on meta are actually kind of good I
mean people kind of talk about it a
little bit and then there's of course
like privacy Circles of like all ads are
bad or whatever some of the Twitter
noise in the communities I'm in will
talk about ads being bad and all this
kind of stuff but when I get on
Instagram I kind of like the ads I
actually had to remove Instagram from my
phone finally because I was getting
enticed by too many products because
it's almost like ads as content that I
actually enjoyed the ads and would
almost go to Instagram not just to see
the content from the people I follow
it's like a great product discovery
engine in a way because they're so good
at targeting you the specific things
that you would be interested in I think
that's another thing it's like the two
biggest players in ads in this context
actually make a ton of sense because
Google is search intent is it when you
go search something you're telling a
text field on the internet that you have
a problem and that you're looking for a
solution and so it makes sense why
Google can monetize ads at that level
and then with Facebook like it kind of
makes sense how well they do with their
own monetization for helping apps
monetized because the ads are actually
really
good glad to hear that marketers are
doing a good job here yeah I think like
looking at into many ad accounts every
month I think ads could still be better
and I still see a lot of things where I
feel like okay and this is more of like
a very classic Banner ad or something
and it's not really well thought through
but I mean definitely it seems to work
for them that they have been increasing
ad load more and more and users are
still enjoying the experience
so it feels like people get value out of
the ads and not just out of the Native
content because by now I would say like
50% of what you see on those feeds is
ads or then influencers posting native
content but then they do product
placements so it's really much of a
product discovery engine as you
mentioned here and then the web is like
the opposite kind of to your point
earlier like banner ads tabula ads on
news sites it's like the ad experience
on the web broadly is actually the exact
opposite of that including Google's
display networks and things like that
that they do and then especially the way
Google and we're not going to talk much
about Google today but the ways that
Google forces you to do these broad
campaigns that might end up in these
really poor display ad networks versus
the kind of higher intent with meta it's
like you know your ad is going to show
up in these quality higher intent places
even versus Google that actually brings
me to the next question I wanted to ask
you is that how do you think about
Facebook in the G Channel mix for a
subscription app as they're scaling up
to me it would usually be one of the
first channels to launch because it's a
Discovery Channel you know you can get
some volume there and it's a bit more
representative of an audience you will
Target in the future than for example
search search is super interesting
because you know the quality behind it
so if you're trying to validate your
funnel your pricing strategy then Apple
search ads might be an interest one just
so that you know you're buying
qualitative traffic and don't have to
worry about was my ad good did I reach
the Right audience because you know if
someone searches for a weather app and
you have a weather app then you can be
sure it's the right user but it's not as
scalable it's super competitive so it's
going to be hard for you to compete with
the big players that might have a better
funnel higher pricing So Meta really
stands out because you can have a
competitive advantage through good
creative and through mastering the
channel and that's why I like to start
it early on and most apps care about iOS
a little bit more than Android which
also gives meta a competitive advantage
over Google ads because Google tends to
be very strong on Android where they own
the ecosystem it's much easier for them
to track performance while on iOS
they've rather been struggling in the
recent years all right so with the
broader context out of the way I wanted
to dive into history which may seem odd
but I do think is important in the
context of meta ads because there has
been a lot that's changed over the last
four to five years and of course
everybody listening to this podcast will
know what I'm alluding to and that's app
tracking transparency and so before app
tring
transparency meta was the go-to channel
because with a level of deterministic
measurement with the idfa it was just
like magic for so many apps and and I
think it's maybe even lost on folks who
don't follow the industry super close
but a lot of the apps that are big today
are big specifically because of the
Arbitrage of them having scaled so
quickly so efficiently on meta ads preat
and then ATT happened so tell me I mean
maybe I've already given enough of the
history but like what's your perspective
on the preat and then we'll get into
like how ATT changed and how things are
evolving definitely it's a bit unfair of
like how much easier things were back in
the days compared to today So Meta Rel
had one of the strongest device graphs
out there so they really built super
strong customer profiles based on these
idas and as I already mentioned they
just tracked everything everyone had the
meta SDK everyone had a pixel on their
website from them so basically they were
tracking the whole internet and were
able to create these super strong
customer profiles with ATT that changed
making things a bit harder maybe a small
anecdote like most of my preat time I
spent in the gaming industry working for
in games a big German strategy games
developer and yeah I followed the whole
development from like browser games into
mobile games and we started meta as a
channel somewh around like
2012 2013 when I joined the company and
we scaled it super rapidly always
jumping on the newest products when they
launched app event optimization for the
first time when they launched value
optimization for the first time those
were always magic moments in the end
like it was really a gold rush we turned
those campaigns on we didn't have to
care about targeting anymore they were
just looking for the right customers for
us and we were within the month doubling
our budget again and again while
overachieving our return on investment
targets and it was crazy like we had
times where management told us please
don't spend so much money we know it
looks amazing but we're scared that's
how it worked back then and that just
really changed with ATT and you have to
do your homework a lot more closely
these days you have to dive deeper into
like your funnel into creative strategy
and do a lot more qualitative work while
back in the days it was really data
driven you could push out just a ton of
creatives meta would find the Right
audience for them and you didn't even
have to care like why did this work it's
like okay it works we're just going to
do it over and over again and that's
kind of the biggest change that happened
with the implementation of ATT so as
attt rolled out it feels like there was
an especially tumultuous year year 18
months two years where things just
weren't working what were you seeing
during those times or what lessons can
you take from that time and then it does
seem like and we'll get to this that
things have started improving but tell
me about for history's sake what was
that like 18 months to two years like as
somebody spending a ton of money on
behalf of clients and Publishers trying
to make it work thankfully actually
around that time I moved from a UA focus
into growth Focus so I had some time
where I could dig into the topic before
I was spending bigger budgets again
which was great but I mean the main
issue was there was a lot of uncertainty
really around what's going to happen and
what this is going to look like I think
the whole communication by Apple wasn't
great and for the longest time it wasn't
clear what this would do to your data
models what this would do to meta's
algorithm and those things really only
were figured out as it was life and then
we saw a massive drop in performance
everyone skilled back meta's stock took
a hit and their advertising income took
a hit and only from there on things
recovered so I think probably there
would have been ways to make this
transition a bit smoother but this was
just what we had to deal with and I
think like advertisers really had to
relearn how to make predictions on how
valuable this channel actually is
because you don't have down funnel
tracking anymore most apps only track a
trial start within their ads manager and
that's all they see they don't know
what's happening afterwards do these
people convert do they renew how long do
they stick around which put meta in a
bit of a tough position because it's
always been a more expensive channel in
the end on the upper funnel cpms are
high there's a lot of pressure in the
auction very competitive but the value
came with that great targeting and the
good down funnel performance so
conversion rates were often higher for
this traffic which is something you now
weren't able to see and you also were
unsure if meta is still doing a good job
and that of course
creates a lot of uncertainty and you
don't want to spend a million a month
without knowing is this going to be
profitable in the end and that was the
main issue that took one to two years I
would say now that advertisers are in a
more comfortable position again they've
find you their data models so that they
can predict value based on that trial
event and all the other information that
they're Gathering From users in
onboarding now at what point did you
start seeing a shift because I I feel
like maybe it's you specifically that
I've been following on LinkedIn for a
while it feels feel like it's not just
you but that I've just been hearing more
and more folks say in the last I don't
know 12 months or so and then especially
again specifically for subscription apps
that it's like working again so how much
of that is Facebook having invested so
much into these targeting algorithms and
non-deterministic measurement and those
things how much of it's like Publishers
getting smarter like you were talking
about like what are all the contributing
factors to it start stting to get better
again and then when did you start seeing
that shift happen to me it also feels
like there was a shift definitely in the
last year again while also already prior
to that like the best advertisers
definitely didn't take until a year ago
like they were already ramping this up
again much quicker and I think it's a
combination of these factors really it's
not just I mean meta of course keeps
improving the algorithm and gets better
at modeling performance again based on
the signals that they're getting from
scan but also from
much more videos on the platform now I
mean they're scaling reals like crazy
most of my accounts is actually one of
the biggest placements by now and it
functions a lot more like Tik Tok so
they have a lot of Engagement signals
watch rates which they can feed into the
algorithm and based on that I think they
got pretty good at modeling performance
even from these very upper funnel
metrics and on the other hand also
advertisers just got better and better
and I think by now everyone has covered
the groundwork and they know we need
like a where did you hear about a
service green onboarding so that we can
create sample data on channel level and
look into differences of organic versus
meta versus Tik Tok most advertisers are
asking for age and gender of users which
is super helpful because meta always
reports you their data on agent gender
level and if you then in your product
also apply that level again then you can
basically cross check and look into I
don't know I'm seeing in my app that age
group 45 to 54 is 5X more valuable than
18 to 24 so is my CPI of 18 to 24
actually 5x lower or is there a mismatch
and these other kind of things that I
think first really needed to be dealt in
and then data models needed to be
improved so that advertisers really gain
a lot more trust again in what they're
spending on these platforms yeah I think
that's a really good summary and again I
think this is all going to be super
helpful to folks who've heard oh things
are changing like is it time to like
come back to the platform or if we
didn't find success in
2021 what can we do today differently
that will find success and I think
understanding this kind of context of
why it was so good preat the kind of
tumultuous time and then why it's
starting to get better I think is super
helpful for people to kind of frame
their decisions around when and how to
be ramping up meta ads so the last thing
on this topic though before we move on
is scan three and we'll talk about scan
4 because I haven't fully ramped that up
yet but how much do you think scan three
has helped and then how has it helped
with meta getting better at finding
these users again like most advertisers
are really not happy with what scan 3
can do still compared to what things
look like beforehand you really have a
very limited time frame that you can
track users you have privacy thresholds
meaning you need a certain level of
installs per day so that you can
actually get a post back with your app
events attached to it and also there is
postback delay so it usually takes two
to three days for your posts to arrive
and then you need to match that to what
you've been doing two to three days ago
so your spend levels from three days ago
need to match the app events that you're
receiving three days after which isn't
great I mean you want your data to feel
like it's scientific and you can rely on
it and this always feels a bit Scrappy
and it's not great based on what you've
did before but still scan 3 I think has
allowed a lot of advertisers to spend a
lot more money again and especially sub
apps were a bit in a comfortable
position because their payment usually
happens in onboarding already so you
start a trial event there meaning you
have a pretty good value indicator early
on in the product experience that you
can feedback to that model so that meta
at least gets a post back within these
two to three days while other
advertisers were hit a lot more strongly
like talking about gaming before for
games usually monetization happened not
as fast still like good payers would
already purchase something early on but
a lot of especially in the strategy
games genre the whole business model was
based on some people paying a lot and
finding these people got a lot harder
because signal quality isn't as strong
they might not pay that big amount of
money on the first day meaning you can't
track it and hence meta can't find you
these people anymore so any product that
was a bit more Niche with purchase
patterns that were later in the product
basically had a hard time and hence also
product development and how you treat
your funnel played a big role here so
really if you want to succeed on scan
you have to work a bit deeper into
product and think about what are my
conversion events going to be what can I
feed to these platforms so they still
make smart decisions for me and luckily
sub apps just were in a good position
for having that trial and onboard
I want to dive into fast practices I'm
sure folks listening are like all right
now tell me what to do but before we
transition to that I did want to get any
other kind of thoughts around how to
think about subscription apps why they
work so well on meta and then you know a
lot of the noise around at was even
around DTC direct to Consumer kind of
physical products and things like that
so any other top of Mind differences so
when somebody reads ah meta is not
performing but it's from like a dtoc
perspective how do they frame their
thinking around that compared to running
a subscription app and trying to scale a
subscription app on meta I mean I would
actually say that d2c has an easier game
because most of what their tracking is
still happening on the web and so you
have Facebook conversion API that you
can send your pixels through directly
your events through directly from
Shopify there's an easy integration and
then you're out of this whole at mess if
if you're trying to send traffic into
your app for like a bigger I don't know
fashion brand or something that is
trying to optimize for app traffic that
might be a bit tough but as you're on
web I've seen actually that d2c
advertisers had a much easier game and
also a lot of the recent uptick I think
was actually from d2c and the whole
Advantage Plus initiatives that were
launched from meta so they really
automated more and more of what's
happening in the app account for the
better or the worse depending on what
you're looking at I think for d2c it
works nice because they are sending a
purchase event which is their business
goal in the end and the algorithm knows
this person has purchased potentially
even for how much while if you send a
trial event the algorithm can't be as
strong for you because it's not directly
correlated with business value a trial
only converts in 30 to 50% of cases so
they might be optimizing for the other
70% basically I've seen stronger
performance in these d2c accounts d2c is
maybe better better which that's
interesting I hadn't heard it framed
quite that way so again really good to
get that perspective and then games and
delayed monetization is maybe where
things are still going to struggle any
other thoughts on subscription apps and
how they vary against other types of ads
on meta yeah I think the conversion
event is really the most important one
so like as I mentioned your trial isn't
a real business value for you in the end
and trial conversion can vary massively
on an audience level I already mentioned
on AG group it's usually big differences
older people will just convert better
because they have deeper Pockets so
that's where it's special on the
subscription front because you need to
be much more aware of what's Happening
after the trial and guide the algorithm
in the right direction while a d2c
Advertiser will probably get along with
using more of the automation because the
algorithm is just much closer to their
actual business goal I mean they also
have recurring purchases and people that
sign up for the email list and don't so
I don't want to say it's easy game for
them or they less skilled but definitely
there are special complications with
advertising a subscription app and
optimizing for trial all right well
let's move into best practices and so
we've talked about all the challenges
how do you as a subscription app best
use meta to find those payers that are
actually going to become subscribers I
mean I think it's pretty commonly known
that you want to use a Consolidated
account structure so that you really try
to maximize the amount of signal you get
on each of your adsets so in the end as
the algorithm is supposed to help you
find your users you want to maximize the
signals that it has to basically do that
and in the account you have a campaign
level at set level at level and if you
set things up very granularly and you
might be running I don't know 10
campaigns with 50 adsets in them you
would be scattering data across all of
these so the algorithm will have a very
tough time in actually using those
signals to find your users while if you
just run one campaign with one adset in
it all that data will be used to
basically fine tune targeting for you so
you always want to find the right
balance of where do I need granularity
to guide the algorithm and maybe you
want a country split in your campaigns
because you know the us is going to be
much more profitable than Brazil so you
want to have these splits but then still
don't add too many so that there's a lot
of signal under each of your campaigns
that would then maybe be something that
as you scale up so like if you're just
starting out and you're spending that
first 40K to like start figuring out if
you can get the algorithm trained that's
when you want to be almost completely
Consolidated and then as you're spending
more and more and more then maybe you do
have more flexibility to branch that
pretty much so yeah try to start very
Consolidated and then as you're adding
span you can add additional campaigns
and adsets based on the levels that you
want to Target separately and this is
also going to really help you pass
privacy thresholds which are in scan 3
is still a big pain for especially
smaller advertisers because you need to
reach 88 installs per day per scan
campaign ID and actually meta doesn't
even tell you where they apply a scan
campaign ID it's definitely on adset
level but it might even be more Nara
because they receive better data on each
of these IDs so they might be creating
in the background two IDs for Facebook
and for Instagram even though you target
these in one campaign it might be two
IDs you don't know so basically you want
to make sure a lot of installs are
coming through on each of your campaigns
so that privacy thresholds are passed
and then you actually get postbacks in
so that meta sees your trials and can
optimize for you so start Consolidated
don't go in there set up different
interest targeting and think that you
know better than the algorithm because
in the end you don't so are there any
scan specific best practices or at this
point does meta handle most of that for
you like when you install the Facebook
SDK is there customization and best
practices on scan or is that mostly just
kind of like handled by the SDK and by
default I mean I would say one best
practice is to optimize for your trial
event and make sure that's basically the
highest value one in your scan schema
other than that there is not much you
need to handle in terms of how you set
up your campaigns you have a choice
choice between tracking through scan and
through a it's really not that you need
to take special care of a scan campaign
by setting it up differently what you
need to consider is how you evaluate
your data because as I mentioned before
your events are going to come in later
so you actually when you kick off your
campaign for two days you're not going
to see any results and that can be scary
especially if you're spending a lot and
it says you've spent 5K and you have
zero installs and zero trial tracked but
that's just due to the fact that
postbacks are coming in delayed and you
need to make sure that you're basically
evaluating campaigns that way and always
match data from two days back with the
right spend level additionally I would
say also give meta a little bit more
time because they don't get these events
super quickly so you shouldn't be
evaluating results after three four days
because then only one day of data came
in meaning the algorithm wouldn't have
been able to really do a good job for
you yet so give it some time at least a
week I would say before you start
evaluating performance that's kind of
the biggest thing to take care of when
you're handling a scan campaign because
of that is a 3-day free trial a better
tactic even if maybe you're not going to
convert quite as well but you're going
to get better data on a three-day trial
than a 7-Day free trial or do both kind
of work well as long as you know that
and are factoring that into your data
measurement in the end right now in scan
3 it's not going to make a big
difference I mean yeah for conversion
there might be one or the other will be
better for your app but you're still
only going to track your trial start
event and then you're going to have to
look into TR conversion in your product
data and of course having a 3-day window
means you're getting a conversion
quicker meaning you can more quickly
evaluate your results but that's really
the only benefit here and I would say if
a 7-Day trial is actually converting
five 10% better for you then rather go
with that and don't reduce performance
just so that you have results quicker
because over time your modeling and
knowledge over that data will become
strong enough that you can also predict
results with a 7-Day trial what are your
other kind of best practices on the
basic level and then we can get to like
more advanced stuff with the
subscription app you're always going to
optimize for a trial start generally
like try to get your conversion event as
close to a business value that you can
for the subscription app it's mainly
going to be that don't Target to narrow
these algorithms usually need a lot of
reach so that they can use data to then
find the Right audience for you if you
apply a ton of targeting restrictions on
top then usually you pay a premium for
targeting more granularly while
performance not necessarily is better so
I would usually with a new app rather
start with a broad targeting choose your
core markets and I do usually exclude
younger users below 25 sometimes even
below 30 depending on app because of
what I mentioned earlier that the
conversion rate from trial to paid is so
different for older and younger users
and while you're still early and you
don't have a good understanding yet of
how this is going to convert I rather
start a bit more conservatively use only
audiences that I know have a good chance
of converting and only once I've
gathered data and get a better
understanding I might broaden that to
like 25 plus but really the age group
below 25 is really neglected by most of
the advertisers because they are usually
very cheap to buy because they use
social media more often and they don't
have high purchasing power so cpms are
low meta really loves spending on them
because they're so cheap and they're
going to create a cheap cost per trial
but then the conversion down funnel is
going to be very very poor so I haven't
seen anyone really correct this issue
yet of how can you spend towards these
audiences and still convert them with I
don't know a good discount strategy or
whatever you might be apply in the back
to it and yeah 25 plus is kind of the
best practice I would say in the
industry and one other thing is I
already mentioned like meta also pushing
for Advantage Plus more and more which
is their automation features you by now
will see probably 10 different things
that are called Advantage Plus in the UI
which gets very confusing at times and
it's basically what you mentioned with
Google before that they are trying to
make you opt into everything that
maximizes reach on their end so that
they can sell away any kind of inventory
for some advertisers it works very very
well especially if your conversion event
again is close to your business goal but
with a trial just be careful I wouldn't
say it's not a strategy to use but you
want to know the algorithm Works before
allowing the algorithm to do everything
for you so I usually start on manual
campaigns set up things myself have
separate adsets per country and then
exclude younger age groups while only
later in the lifetime of an account I
might layer on these fully automated
campaigns because then I know okay my
conversion rate for these users is going
to be that much lower so I'm bidding
less aggressively on them to have a cost
per trial that is cheaper so that the
equation works out be skeptical of all
that automation meta likes to kind of
append recommended labels to everything
but it's not really recommended for
everyone for sure you kind of mentioned
you don't want to go super narrow on
your targeting but then you mention you
do want to Target via age so you're
saying there is some level of penalty in
the auction in a way like you're going
to just have to pay more in the auction
to get these holder users but that's the
one place where being more granular and
your targeting really tends to pay off
yeah with h definitely that's the
biggest lever if you're struggling with
traal conversion rate then Target older
people and you're meally going to bring
it up if you need good numbers for your
next VC round then that's definitely a
good a good trick to make those numbers
look better are there any more kind of
Advanced Techniques that you start to
get into as you scale that people should
be aware of there's a few ones I would
want to highlight that I tend to see in
accounts where people just stay a bit
too basic and don't optimize on that
deeper level to really fully leverage
that channel one of those I would say is
creative diversity which is linked with
placement performance and really
optimizing for each of these placements
as you already mentioned there's a ton
by now I also don't know all of them by
heart anymore but really there is
totally different audiences behind any
of these with some it's really different
apps like Facebook versus Instagram but
then also on Instagram the people that
use the Instagram feed compared to the
people that use Instagram reals are
totally different reals is much closer
to a Tik Tok audience it's younger lower
intent while the feed is a bit more
qualitative but also usually more
expensive so you really want to find out
like what are the placements that I can
find my target audience on and from
there go really deep into optimizing
your creative for these placements so
you want to actually use these apps if
you find Facebook is still working for
me then use Facebook you probably
haven't been on there in a while but it
changed a lot people still use it and
you want to know like what does this
placement look like what's the typical
content people are sharing here and how
can I insert an ad here that makes sense
that is close to the same experience so
it's not just a banner ad like on a
website but you want to really work with
this native feeling and I feel that's
where often people just look at
performance on a too high level they
look at okay this creative has had a
cost per trial of 10 EUR and the other
one has 15 so one has done better than
the other but you really want to dig
into okay where did I deliver with these
and meta shares all that data you can
always break down creative performance
on a placement level on an age level on
a gender level so you can learn a lot
really about where do I need to run
these ads to get good performance in my
app and creative strategy is really
where it's at then so that you tailor
things to the right placements that are
going to serve you well gotcha and then
of course once you've run the ad so much
of the potential performance for that ad
ends up being what then happens in your
app how do you think about the funnel
optimization from onboarding to pay
placement to surveys to other things
that are going to happen happen early in
that product journey in ways to kind of
optimize that toward being more
successful on meta yeah that's
definitely one of the changes I would
say I've seen that UA managers need to
be more and more product focused as well
and they need to look into full funnel
performance not just purely on the ad
side because much of that efficiency
from the algorithm is gone and you need
to find additional levers to improve
performance and I try to always use meta
as my channel for experimentation to
find angles that I can use for
advertising certain like copywriting
that works well and styles and then take
my winners and inform my full funnel
with it so if I found something is
working very well on meta then I can
bring these learnings into abore
optimization easily oftentimes it's as
easy as reusing your ad as a video or
just a screenshot of it in your app
store so if meta is one of your main
channels then that already creates
coherence people click through they see
I've landed in the right place and this
is the app that I was looking at that
often already creates an uplift and you
can take that then also down the funnel
if you found that okay we are seeing
best results from an audience on
Facebook with this type of creative that
is between 35 and 44 and female of
course there's a lot in there that you
can hypothesize around to create
experiments throughout your funnel and
tailor to that audience if you showcase
reviews in your boarding then you might
want to take a user review from someone
that is actually in that demographic or
at least make it look like it I mean you
can always just say this is from a woman
44 from the US for example Additionally
you also want to make sure that other
parts of that onboarding really work in
sync with what you're trying to achieve
on meta so if you are for example
driving a lot of traffic through res and
you're targeting relatively young users
you're pricing needs to fit that
strategy and I often see a mismatch
there where people are using a lot of
these ugc videos these days user
generated content Styles so it's like
someone filming themselves on their
phone talking to the camera and just why
they're loving this product basically
and this video style is what's native to
real placements and it's portrait mode
short form usually below 30 seconds and
that placement drives younger traffic
but if your app actually I mean maybe
your app is already tailored to older
users which means you shouldn't be doing
this anyways but even if it's an app
that is a bit younger and your pricing
is very high let's say 80 90 bucks a
year you're going to have a hard time
converting these people because they're
just not as high intent and don't have
as much purchasing power so your pricing
what your pay wall looks like in the
onboarding needs to be really synced up
with the ads you're running and the
placements you're on so that things even
get a chance to convert are there any
signals that you get in the app from
Facebook like I know back before
at you could actually get from the
Facebook SDK the specific ad or Channel
or you got a lot of very granular data
where you could even personalize your
onboarding and your pay wall and pricing
or anything else based on even the
specific ad they saw do you get any
signals from Facebook now or do you
pretty much have to do that
personalization based on a short survey
or other context um you don't get any
data anymore really it's all aggregate
mostly you don't even know the amount of
traffic coming from meta because what's
tracked with scan often has a bigger
discrepancy often around even 50% of
Trials are under reported so what you
get is an aggregate number that is not
all the users and you don't know like
which specific user came from the
channel so that's why it's super
important to really have an onboarding
that enriches that data again so that
you ask questions how old are you what's
your gender where did you hear about us
and the data you gather here is never
going to match like what's happening on
the UA front one to one it's not that
you can ask users where did you come
from and then only attribute the ones
that said I came from meta because a
user Journey usually looks a lot
different from like just seeing one ad
and clicking on something so they might
have heard about your app from a friend
then they saw a meta app but in the
survey they're still going to answer I
heard about you from a friend because
that was the first touch point so it's
really just meant to create these data
samples that allow you to compare and
you're going to see differences in
someone that answered I came from Tik
Tok compared to someone that answers I
came from matter for sure and same for
age groups which is then the data that
you can use to personalize and to inform
your data modeling to actually know how
valuable your user acquisition efforts
are to you and then how are you doing
this measurement like you've talked
several times about modeling and I guess
maybe we should talk about this at
different levels like when you're first
starting out how do you think about that
measurement and probably not even like
fully modeling you might not even have
like a data warehouse that you're
dumping product data and analytics data
and everything else into how do you
think about then measuring this yeah
usually as soon as people have like a
data warehouse and an analytics team
then I don't need to do that work
anymore so what I do is usually a bit
more MVP which is really using a few
data sources to build trust in the
channel and one of them is
incrementality so you want to switch ads
on switch ads off and see what's
happening to your Baseline which is
always of course a good position for
smaller developers if you don't have a
ton of organic yet if you don't have 10
channels running it's going to be much
easier to see okay I'm spending now 2K a
day on meta and my Baseline has
increased by 50% that's probably the
effect from the ads the more advanced
you are the more you will need a data
science team for this because the
fluctuations on your Baseline are going
to be much smaller and it's going to be
harder to see what's going on to other
data points going into this are your ATT
optin audience so there's still a
smaller set of users that you are able
to match to a channel as you were used
to back then so that again creates a
sample where you can see I don't know 5%
of people I was able to match on meta 6%
I was able to match on Tik Tok and I can
compare how valuable are these so just
to inform should my cost per trial on
meta be 3x 4X higher on Tik Tok or
should it be a lot cheaper because
traffic quality is less than that the
other one is this where did you hear
about a survey so that users actually
give you a qualitative answer on this is
the channel I came from which can be a
third input into this model and from
there it's really a bit of setting your
cost per trial goals accordingly so that
you know meta is always 2x as valuable
as Tik Tok we need to adjust our cost
per trials based on that level gotcha
and then as folks scale up what are you
seeing with these more sophisticated
apps working and tooling too I mean at
what point do you layer on an MMP or if
Facebook's your only channel are you
just dumping everything into a data
warehouse and having your internal
analytics team do aspects of what an MMP
would be doing for you anyway yeah I
mean you don't need an MMP to run meta
they have their own SDK that you can
Implement and you can insert your scan
model there um track your Tri event and
then it's doing the job depending on
what your Ambitions are how quick you
want to scale I would say like if you're
a small developer start out with that
and don't add on additional tooling
because it creates another breaking
point something can always go wrong and
also it's going to cost you money at
some point I mean usually there's a bit
of a free plan in the beginning if you
have very few TR events but then it
quickly gets to be another cost center
and usually like Revenue cat is even one
of the tools that is used for these
early devs to like look into then trial
performance how do my trials convert
into paid how is that different on a
country level and that would even inform
modeling so really I think like most of
the de developers I'm working with are
like 10 to 20 people teams and they
don't have very s sophisticated tooling
for this yet and it's not really needed
at this early stage when you say
modeling I mean this is spreadsheets and
intuitive quote unquote modeling not
necessarily like having to build an
algorithm to be creating some
sophisticated matching and all that kind
of stuff it's more looking at your data
half of the models kind of in your head
as you're running the ads looking at the
data kind of making decisions based on
that right yeah it's not super
sophisticated as I said it's very very
Scrappy it's really just getting an
understanding of the audience that
you're driving how valuable it is on a
country level AG level and a channel
level and then setting your cost per
trial gos accordingly and of course
don't forget about also rechecking if
your assumptions are right because it's
always just assumptions so if you're
assuming I can spend 50k a month on meta
and will get my money back within I
don't know maybe even instant payback so
on day eight after the tri converts then
check your actuals like don't rely on
just the modeling but make sure that
you're actually recouping money in the
time frame that you're predicted it
would happen but often in the early days
it's quite Scrappy and then as teams
grow they would collect all of this in a
data warehouse usually have someone that
is a bit more skilled in all of this so
a data engineer analytics person who
then looks into how can we create a
predictive model and take in all our UA
data what we have on scan what we get
from the MMP and feed a UA manager then
with a estimated Ras pretty quickly so
that they can take decisions but with
most of the teams I've seen even bigger
ones it was still at that Scrappy level
because as I said it's not scientific
anyways it's all just predictions so I
haven't seen anyone of the small to
midsize teams getting super Advanced on
it yeah one of the things I I think a
lot about to kind of seeing behind the
scenes at Revenue cat you know as we
roll out things like our experiments
feature and even our charts and so many
other things we have 30,000 developers
now and all checking our math on
everything we find bugs that we have to
fix but like we're finding all the bugs
because we're working with so many
different developers with so many
different needs and find so many
different edge cases but I often think
about that like any one app if you are a
larger app and you've created this
sophisticated algorithm and you have a
data team you still need to be going
back and at very high levels and in less
sophisticated ways like double-checking
all of those assumptions because one
little like mismatched SQL query is just
going to blow things up in a way that's
going to cost you a lot of money and so
like while as you grow you can get more
sophisticated you need to be careful
about that sophistication because things
can go wrong and do go wrong totally
totally yeah even back in the days when
I was working gaming and everything was
still tracked on an idfa level we had
very Advanced models on all of this
predicting lifetime value for the next
two years but those were usually built
on like h amounts of data and then I'm
optimizing on an ad level and of course
a model can go wrong the more granular
you go and a big part of the job was
really digging into that data and
proving the data team that they're
making a wrong assumption and my ads
might actually be doing better than they
think they are so definitely always go
back also like check historic data you
had an assumption now you have three
months worth of data look into how did
this perform is it better or worse than
what I had predicted to find you this
over time yeah and then by definition
any model breaks as you make big changes
so like you said three months ago you
have a Bas line and you think it was
working and then you roll out a big new
feature well that breaks your model by
definition because those assumptions
that went into the model that has been
working now doesn't work because you
have new features that you're promoting
in a way that may be greates higher
intent and drives higher value per user
and things like that so yeah I mean it's
funny how Scrappy teams in some ways are
better off because you're just doing the
math in simpler ways and the more
sophisticated it gets the more places it
can break it's just a matter of being
smart about it and triple checking
assumptions and not forgetting the
basics when you're doing all this kind
of stuff if the UA team also handles the
modeling themselves then it's much
easier to get these changes in while
once another team is actually
responsible for it then it's company
politics and you need to prove them that
maybe something needs to be changed and
that just makes things more complicated
yeah the big elephant in the room we
haven't discussed yet is creative and
that's like so make or break for these
campaigns so how do you stand out how do
you use these short little interruptions
or content in Facebook and Instagram and
other places to get people's attention
to drive that intent to find the right
audiences I would always recommend like
using these apps and being close to that
content like many people love to dig
through competitor ads to make ads and I
think there is a lot of value in this
especially if you look at big Brands and
you know they're doing well on the
platform but in the end what you're
trying to achieve is that your content
is similar to the content that people
engage with when it's not an ad and for
that you need to be using these
placements and understand what makes
them tick so that would be my biggest
advice here especially talking about
Facebook no one I know my age kind of in
their mid-30s is using Facebook anymore
but for meta ads it's still a super
valuable placement it's a bit older
audience a lot higher purchasing power
so you want to know what's going on
there and how you can tailor to these
audiences I would also recommend like
try to look outside your bubble so
follow some sides that you wouldn't
usually because your target audience
will be a lot more diverse than what
you're looking at so I tend to like
follow for example a broad spectrum of
news sites on Instagram and on Facebook
because I want to see what are the
headlines how click baity are they what
other styles they're using in their
images because then I can tailor my
content to them so while I don't agree
with anything they write I still follow
Fox News on Instagram and Facebook just
to see what's the content some of my
target audience might be consuming yeah
that makes a lot of sense in this new
paradigm where you do especially early
on have to run very Consolidated
campaigns how do you test creative and
how many creatives are you running and
how do you scale that up I would say
like the times are gone where you
created thousands of creatives and you
just throw them in there and hope for
meta to do the job because creative
testing has gotten a lot more expensive
and data quality has decreased so you
want to be a bit more in charge and make
more qualitative bets here so my
creative testing volume has gone down
quite a bit in terms of best practice
structure always test your creatives in
a separate campaign not in the one that
you're scaling and that is running
smoothly because it will interrupt them
and things can go wrong there's this
Infamous learning phase so whenever you
make a change to your running campaign
it resets it meaning the campaigner
recalibrates and that can lead to
fluctuations and performance so if you
upload a new creative into your skilled
campaign you want to make sure it's a
good one you want to have tested
beforehand and know this is actually
going to improve performance and not
decrease it and other than that I always
try to test them in a similar
environment that I'm also scaling in so
I don't know if my scale campaign is
optimizing for trial and I have 10 core
markets that I usually advertise in then
my testing campaign is going to run in
the cheapest of those markets but in the
ones that I'm also Al in and it's also
going to optimize for a trial it's not
going to be a totally different campaign
setup which I often see advertisers do
because they want to save money and they
only optimize for an install and they go
into markets like Thailand or Mexico
where there's cheap ctms but then the
audience is going to be a lot different
if you're not live in these markets you
usually then of course people haven't
heard of your brand yet so the effect
there is going to be different so I
rather try to be a bit closer to my
actual audience when testing it's going
to be more expensive but then results
are just going to be easier to Port over
to my skill campaign the last thing I
did want to talk about real quick is the
future and like meta has already made
some advancements scan 4 is coming out
does the future look bright for
continuing to improve upon the
improvements we've already seen and then
what are the things that are
contributing or potentially going to
contribute to increasing performance
over time yeah I would say yeah the
future does look bright scan for as you
said is on the horizon there are a lot
of things in there that are going to
help you with the channel two main
benefits I see is for one privacy
thresholds are coming down so it's now
called crowd and unimited tiers and
based on some First Data that EPS Flyers
shared from what they see in their
client data it's only going to be 20
installs per day down from 88 which is
quite the difference and especially for
more Niche advertisers that have high
cpis it's going to make a difference for
sure and the other big thing is that
we're getting these two additional post
backs and that's also very interesting
to again feed that model so we have the
word that you hear about us data the at
optin audience and now on top we can
also look at the scan second and third
post back just to F that model and look
into what does my trial to paid
conversion look like from first to third
post back on meta compared to Tik Tok
compared to Google which is going to get
you even more Security in what you're
doing there the other things happening
we mentioned it quickly before was a
which is aggregate event measurement
it's basically metas form of
fingerprinting it's been a bit of a buzz
I see some people saying hey just like
switch everything over to a you're going
to have same data as you used to before
scan others are a lot more cautious I'm
a bit in the middle there I think it is
a great tool and I've seen advertisers
that this really helped especially the
ones that have high cpis and can pass
privacy thresholds so basically with
aggregate event measurement they're
getting instant postp data and meta is
basically just doing the magic on the
back end but also in the end is a
blackbox everything is modeled they're
just looking into kind of IP addresses
and trying to match these users and then
add their modeling on top hence you
cannot really trust it neither can you
scan because there is discrepancies but
I would say be a bit cautious about it
because Apple might take that away as
well like if your whole strategy is
based on running am campaigns and you
don't invest into your scan
infrastructure and how you evaluate
performance under scan then at any point
you might be in the similar situation to
when at launched so I like to build my
account foundation on scan because I
know it's future proof it's what's Apple
wants us to do and it's also getting
better with each version I mean scan 5
is already on the horizon while we've
been waiting a long time for scan 4 to
be finally rolled out and then I use a
for scaling if I see performance is good
with it then why not use that
opportunity I wouldn't just not do it
because it's unsecure I rather take my
chance there but it shouldn't be the
foundation and your P Performance Based
on it because you can't be sure what's
going to happen when do you expect scan
and four to be rolled out enough where
we're going to fully see the benefits I
have no idea I also don't want to take
guesses I would have expected it to
happen way faster because of these
benefits but like the whole industry has
been quite slow there is this nice
singular tracker from where you can see
basically the post backs that are coming
on scan 4 versus scan 3 for all the
different networks and meta has ramped
up to like 40% scan for some when
February I think now they actually went
back down to 20% again so I have no idea
when it's going to happen and this is
already their second attempt at rolling
it out like the last one was somewh back
in September 2023 so they seem to be
taking their time they seem to not be
really sure yet how to make sense of the
new postp data and hence I won't make
any guesses but yeah I'm excited for it
because of the benefits that I mentioned
and there are a few more where data
granularity is just going to be better
on this model well that's a good place
to wrap it's nice to kind of leave on a
high note that not only has it gotten
better in the last couple years but that
it's likely to get even better not to
dive to chase another rabbit as we wrap
up but it is like personally frustrating
to me that scan 4 is probably what scan
two should have because scan 2 is what
Apple rolled out when at was rolled out
and had they spent more time talked to
the industry like really understood the
problem of measurement better before
rolling out at I think we'd be in a way
better place today and we could have
avoided a lot of the challenges of the
last few years I'm always frustrated
with apple and how slow they are I was
so frustrated with Apple pay was like
why don't you just pay all these
Merchants to like install the new
hardware and take Apple pay and let's
get the show on the road well like
they're patient and it's fully you
rolled out and almost nowhere I go
doesn't take Apple pay anymore and so
it's like they're patient and eventually
it gets there and so I think that's at
least a hopeful place to end the podcast
is that scan 4.0 is coming and it's
going to keep improving and scan 5.0 and
scan 6.0 and like it is going to get
better and I mean the cool thing like
personally I'm a bit of a privacy Zealot
myself and so it is exciting too that as
someone who cares about privacy and not
wanting to have my user data just
hoovered up by a million different
people and selling data and all the
kinds of things that have gone on preat
it's exciting to me that all of this is
happening in a privacy friendly way that
you're not having to violate user
privacy to do it that's all pretty
exciting to me totally and I really like
like how the job has changed due to this
I really like that you have to go deeper
and go into qualitative data and I don't
know like doing user interviews is super
helpful because you learn how to do
better advertising and it's not just all
sitting in front of your data analytics
deack and throwing hundreds of ads added
every week but you actually have to do
your homework a little bit better and to
me it's a lot of fun and it's kind of
moved things in the right direction and
of course for Apple there's also the
benefit that Apple search as 5x in
Market size or
something
yeah for those of you who are running
Facebook ads since I'm not you've
probably been like shouting into the
void asking questions that you hope I
would have asked Marcus you know more
advanced questions more tactical
questions the good news is Marcus
actually did an AMA in the sub Club
Community if you go to chat. club.com
and look for the AMA and that's public
you have to join to get to some of the
private channels but we've been doing
public amas there on the subclub
community so he's actually answered a
lot of kind of more tactical questions
in that ama and then I'm put you on the
spot but I want to have you back on and
do another AMA because you those amas
it's like you know when people are
Flying Blind and not working across
multiple apps like you do it's just so
helpful to be able to talk to an expert
who's doing it so yeah join the
community and we'll do more am with
Marcus with Thomas with other kind of
experts in these fields in the future
and then you can check out what people
already asked Marcus on the AMA that
happened a couple weeks ago so yeah
anything else you wanted to share as you
wrap up I know you're actually accepting
clients right so if people do need to
scale and as much as they've learned
from this podcast maybe still need a
helping hand are you open to clients
right now yeah always happy to kind of
work on fun challenges I have a big
backlog due to LinkedIn going quite well
but basically I'm always looking for
like a fun challenge so feel free to
reach out give me a follow on LinkedIn I
try to post every day also more tactical
stuff and feedback has been great so I
think it's useful and I'm also planning
to launch some digital products soon
probably like an email course on meta
ads and how to make it work for
subscription apps so hopefully by the
time this airs I might even already have
a sign up for that on my page so
definitely give that a visit very cool
and we'll have in the show notes links
to his LinkedIn and other places to find
Marcus and U make sure we link to the am
as well check the show notes and get in
touch with Marcus thank you so much this
was a blast like we could have gone two
or three hours but I do try and keep the
podcast around an hour we've gone a
little over but this is so fun thank you
so much for joining me thanks a lot
David was a lot of
fun thanks so much for listening if you
have a minute please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player you can
also stop by chat. sub club.com to join
our private
[Music]
community